Mudit Gupta

E-mail: es14btech11012@iith.ac.in **Phone:** +91-9705731498, +91-9782325393

Education

B.Tech. 2014 — 2018

IIT Hyderabad

Engineering Science => CGPA - 7.55, Minor in Entrepreneurship => CGPA - 9

Summary

I am a passionate Developer, Techy Geek and an Explorer. Interested in Product Management. Worked on projects related to React.js, node.js, Android, GoLang, data analysis, Machine Learning etc. Also worked as Manager for Elan & Nvision IIT Hyderabad (cultural and technical fest of IIT Hyderabad) and E-Cell (Entrepreneurship Cell) IIT Hyderabad. I like to explore and try out various things and so in turn lean a lot of things.

Work experience (Tech)

Aerospike 1st May 2017 — 30th June 2017

Software Engineering Intern

- Developed a production ready Monitoring System for enterprise edition in Golang.
- · Learned various optimisation techniques.
- Used OOP paradigm and design patterns.

Carrot ID December 2015 — March 2016 Developer

- Made a website with Dynamic front-end using React and Redux.
- Followed Agile Development Process

DYDE September 2015 — November 2015

Android App and website front end developer

- Made a static website using bootstrap.
- Made front end of Android app using XML and Java in Android Studio. Used various layouts and views.

Work experience (Non-Tech)

E-Cell IIT Hyderabad April 2016 — April 2017 Manager

- Co-Founded and Organised Megathon which is India's largest and first ever student run Hackathon in association with E-Cell, IIIT Hyderabad with more than 500 participants.
- Leading the startup culture at IIT Hyderabad. I conducted various events, workshops, interactive games and speaker sessions for inspiring and assisting young entrepreneurs in their journey in the world of business.

Elan & Nvision 2017 IIT Hyderabad Manager

April 2016 — April 2017

- Conducted the best fest IIT-H has ever seen with triple the budget and famous personalities performing on stage.
 Leaded a team of 25 Coordinators and around 100 volunteers.
- Took care of Sponsorship and Workshops Deals, Finances, Hospitality and Infrastructure.
- Took care of Fest Management and ensured smooth running of the Fest.

Nvision 2016 June 2015 — April 2016

Marketing Co-ordinator

- Talked and convinced various companies to sponsor our fest.
- Leaded a team of 10 volunteers and trained them.
- Took care of the requirements of our sponsors for various publicity like online publicity and ground publicity.
- · Coordinated with other coordinators and managers for managing the event according to the requirements of our sponsors.

Hunger Torrent Co-Founder

- August 2015 October 2015
- Co-Founded Hunger torrent as food delivery service which was operational at IIT Hyderabad for 2 months.
 Learned about Idea validation, execution of idea and much more.

Projects

• **IDENTIFY FRAUD FROM ENRON EMAIL** (https://github.com/mudit1403/Machine-Learning-Python) -Identifying Enron Employees who may have committed fraud based on the public Enron financial and email dataset.

Key Concepts Demonstrated -

- 1. ML Algorithms naive_bayes, decision tree, svm
- 2. Regression
- 3. k means
- 4. feature selection
- 5. pca. etc.
- Titanic Data Analysis (https://github.com/mudit1403/Titanic-Machine-Learning) Looking at socio-economic status, gender, and age, predict who's and who's not survive the Titanic using Python & Random Forests.

Key Concepts Demonstrated -

- 1. Numpy, Pandas
- 2. Random Forest Using Sklearn
- 3. Data Cleaning
- Meteor Starter Kit (https://github.com/mudit1403/Zen) Made a meteor react react router starter kit and for the demo of that starter kit i made login and registration page using that kit.

Key Concepts Demonstrated -

React with Meteor

Basic routing with React Router

Routes requiring authentication

Working with reactive data

- Tweet Analysis(under the guidance of Prof. Maunendra Sankar Desarkar) Worked on a Machine Learning Classification problem to classify news channel tweets into various categories.
- Detecting Sub-Events associated with the main event (under the guidance of Prof. Srijith pk) (https://github.com/mudit1403/Twitter-Sub-Event).
- Made a multi-terrine bot which can work both as a car and a helicopter.
- Made a 3-D model of play house in solid edge and 3-D printed it.

Skills

- Languages Golang, C, C++, Python, Java, Javascript, Fortran
- WebBased Languages HTML, CSS, JS
- Database Management, PostgreSQL, MongoDb
- Rest API, GraphQL
- Frameworks and Libraries React.js, Reflux, Redux, Meteor, Node.js, Hapi, Express
- Android App Development XML, Java, React Native
- Machine Learning, Data Analysis
- Data Structures
- Solid Edge
- · MATLAB, Octave
- Marketing
- Git

Interests

My interests include

- Learning new things and gaining new experiences.
- · Entrepreneurship.
- Developing new things.
- Product Management

Relevant Courses Done until 6th Sem

- · Computer Networks
- Database Management Systems
- · Applied Machine Learning
- Operating Systems
- Algorithms
- Automata Theory and Theory of Computation
- Data Structures

Relevant Online Courses Done

- Programming Languages Udacity
- Intro to Machine Learning, Intro to Data Analysis -Udacity
- Android Development for Beginners, Developing Android Apps - Udacity
- Intro to Descriptive Statistics, Intro to Inferential Statistics
 Udacity
- Machine Learning (Stanford University) Coursera
- Server-side Development with NodeJs (The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology) - Coursera
- Introduction to Software Product Management (University of Alberta) Coursera

Volunteering

The August Fest - Worked as social media volunteer.

nss - worked as a volunteer for teaching activities, cloth donation etc. for social cause.